# **Rances Rodriguez**

rances.rodrigue@gmail.com • (925) 565 0082 • Oakland

## **Summary**

I'm an HVAC Sheet Metal Worker with 7+ years of experience in commercial HVAC. Proven track record of problem solving, systems thinking, learning and improving my skill set, and reliable and dependable worker. I have both shop and field experience.

### **Professional Experience**

## **ACCO Engineered Systems**

# HVAC Journeyman August 2019 - January 2023

- Specialized in commercial installation of air conditioning and heating systems.
- Built clean rooms at SLAC National Accelerator Laboratory, pharmaceutical laboratories at AbbVie Pharmaceutical, and modern office space for Google, Facebook, Adobe, and various tech companies implementing LEAD construction practices.
- Pressure tested sections of air duct with AirXpress MTC equipment for air leakage to ensure duct systems were within allowable CFM loss according to spec.
- Read blueprints to do layout, scale, measure, mark dimensions and reference lines on floor for wall penetrations, support hangers, and duct ceiling path.
- Installed and fabricated ductwork, VAV boxes, Fire-Smoke dampers using hand and power tools following Fire and Life Safety regulations.

#### Southland Industries

#### **HVAC Apprentice** July 2017 - August 2019

- Specialized in commercial installation of air conditioning and heating systems and prefabrication of duct sections at shop in preparation for transportation to field site.
- Worked on large hospital projects such as UCSF Precision Cancer Medical Building and Sutter Health
  Van Ness installing ductwork, flex duct, ceiling and wall registers, VAV boxes, Fire-Smoke dampers
  using hand and power tools following OSHPD and Fire and Life Safety regulations.
- Rigging for crane picks to lift roof-top Air Handler Units to roof and pulling sections together once on support pads with come-alongs and bolting and sealing to prevent air loss.
- Installed sound attenuators at SFO and Facebook Studios for sound reduction in duct system.

#### **Control Air**

**HVAC Apprentice** January 2016 - August 2017

- Shop work doing sheet metal fabrication.
- Worked in round department building fittings such as square-to-round, Y-branches, conical reducers, round elbows (45° and 90°).
- Operated spot-welders, rollers, plasma table, and pneumatic shears.
- Worked with heavy gauge metal, tac-welded pieces together in preparation for welding (galvanized and stainless steel).
- Insulated fittings and prefabrication of duct sections at shop in preparation for transportation to field site.

# **Education:**

**UC Berkeley** 2007 - 2010

B.A. in Literature of Latin America and Brazil